Lyrics from Genius & Gemini
Made by Randy
(Everything's fine)
（一切都好）
White fish on the coast of the Caribbean, my life is a film
加勒比海岸边的白鱼，我的人生是一部电影
Hero and villain, I'm playin' both in the script
英雄和反派，我在这剧本里扮演着两个角色
Worthy of Spielberg or ChristopherNolan readin'
值得斯皮尔伯格或克里斯托弗·诺兰阅读
The constant overachievin',I know
持续不断的超额完成目标，我知道
I ain't as rich as them people with old money, but I didn't know money
我没有那些拥有旧钱的人富有，但我曾不识金钱为何物
They mock me online for speakin' up on all of our issues
他们嘲笑我在网上对我们所有问题公开发声
And bein'vocal, the shit thatI see on socials
并大声疾呼，说出我在社交媒体上看到的一切
But how can I stay silentwhen, when?
但当我看到这些时，我怎能保持沉默，何时？
I'm out in Barbados, white people mistreatin'locals
我在巴巴多斯，白人对当地人态度恶劣
The villa in Jamaica, but it's owned by the Chinese
牙买加的别墅，却由中国人拥有
Head to the right beach and they're chargin'us five each
走向指定的沙滩，他们向我们每人收取五块钱
They say,"The Caribbean paradise, like, why leave?"
他们说：“加勒比是天堂，为什么离开？
But how can I be silent when there's blood on the pine trees?
但当松树上染有鲜血时，我怎能保持沉默？
Most of us would sacrifice our soul for the right fees
我们大多数人会为了合适的酬劳牺牲灵魂
Before I find love, I'm just prayin'I fnd peace
在我找到爱之前，我只祈祷我能找到平静
You know what I believe,I don't knowif I handled it well
你知道我的信仰，我不知道我是否处理得当
It's forget Coca-Cola, did I stop drinkin'Fanta as well?
去他的可口可乐，那我是否也停止喝芬达了？
I could see the blood on the lyrics I write for myself
我能看到我为自己写的歌词上的鲜血
I cried about slavery, then went to Dubai with my girl
我为奴隶制哭泣，然后却带着我的女友去了迪拜
Surely I ain't part of the problem, I lied to myself
我肯定不是问题的一部分，我对我自己撒了谎
Jewels that my people die for are a sign of my wealth
我族人为此牺牲的珠宝成了我财富的象征
My work is a physical weight of my life and my health
我的工作是我生命和健康的实质重量
The last couple years, felt like I been inside on a shelf
过去几年，感觉自己像被放在架子上，困在里面
I just phoned Cench, and I said,"You inspired myself"
我刚给CentralCee打了电话，我说：“你激励了我”
I don't feel a spot of jealousy inside of myself
我的内心没有一丝嫉妒
But when I'm all alone, I won't lie, I question myself
但当我独自一人时，我不说谎，我质疑自己
AmI self-destructive? Am I doin'the best for myself?
我是自我毁灭吗？我为自己做了最好的选择吗？
I know I love music, but I question the rest of myself
我知道我爱音乐，但我质疑我自己的其他部分
Like why don't you post pictures or why don't you drop music?
比如为什么不发照片或者为什么不发布音乐？
Or why not do somethin' but sittin' and stressin' yourself?
或者为什么不做点什么， 只是一直坐着给自己压力？
Ten years I been in the game and I won't lie, it's gettin' diffcult
我进入这个圈子十年了，不骗你，这正变得困难
This stuff used to be spiritual
这曾是一种精神上的体验
We don't need no commentators, we could leave that to the sports
我们不需要评论员，我们可以把这个留给体育界
Just listen to the music, why do you need somebody's thoughts?
只需听音乐，为什么你需要别人的想法？
And some of it's constructive, but most of it is forced
其中一些是建设性的，但大部分都是强加的
And why we countin' the numbers, how the music make you feel?
我们为什么只计算数字，音乐带给你的感受如何？
I'm just bein'real
我只是说实话
Yeah, white fish on the coast of the Caribbean, my life is a film
耶，加勒比海岸边的白鱼，我的人生是一部电影
Hero and villain, I'm playin' both in the script
英雄和反派，我在这剧本里扮演着两个角色
Worthy of Oscar and Hollywood nominations
值得奥斯卡和好莱坞提名
n throwin'money at women in different denominations and killin' the conversatic
我用不同面额的钱向女人挥洒，终结了对话
All them people told me,"Keep grindin', be patient"
所有人都告诉我 继续努力，保持耐心
It's weird bein'famous, tryna navigate the spaces
成名很奇怪，试图在这些场合中游走
Feel like a celebrity, but you ain't on the A-list
感觉像个名人，但你却不在一线名单上
And you never drop so you ain't really on the playlist
而且你从不发歌，所以你也没在播放列表里
But your fans love you, you can see it on their faces
但你的粉丝爱你，你可以从他们的脸上看到
America feels so close that you can taste it
感觉美国近在咫尺，触手可及
2017, was tryna make it to the ranges
2017年，我努力想进入高档社区
2025年，我努力想进入顶级高尔夫俱乐部（或更富裕的社区）
How do I explain me and my soulmate are strangers, that we've already met
我如何解释我和我的灵魂伴侣是陌生人，我们其实已经相遇
And Ive known her for ages?
而且我已经认识她很久了？
How do I explain, because l'm runnin'out of pages?
我如何解释，因为我的篇幅快用完了？
How do I explain South London and its dangers?
我如何解释南伦敦及其危险？
Can't recall the last time that we was all together, but
想不起我们上次所有人聚在一起是什么时候了，但
All I can remember, the Olympics was in Beijing
我只记得，奥运会在北京举行
Move to Dubai, that's for the taxes that they takin'
搬到迪拜，是为了逃避他们征收的税款
Or move to Qatar,feel the breeze on the beach
或者搬到卡塔尔，感受海滩上的微风
But how can I explain to my kids that it's fake wind?
但我如何向我的孩子们解释那是人造的风？
Free, but I'm broke, have me feelin' like I'm caged in
自由，但我身无分文，让我感觉被困在笼子里
How do I explain two pounds got you eight wings?
我如何解释两英镑就能买到八个鸡翅？
How do I explain my rivals lost, but we ain't win?
我如何解释我的对手输了，但我们也没赢？
Girls I'm around had surgery on their hips
我身边的女孩们对自己的臀部做了手术
How do I explain that I love her the way she is?
我如何解释我爱她本来的样子？
How do I explain my feelings on having kids?
我如何解释我对生孩子的感受？
That it wasn't what it was, but it is what it is
那不是以前的样子，但它就是现在的样子
How do I explain my friends are in the poor neighborhood?
我如何解释我的兄弟们还困在贫民区？
And they don't ask for nothin'even though they know they could
即使他们知道自己可以（求助），1 但他们什么也没求
'Cause they'd rather trap,rob, and get it on their own
因为他们宁愿贩毒、抢劫，靠自己得到
How do I explain these messages on my phone?
我如何解释我手机上的这些信息？
I just got a call, my girl's sittin'in the car
我刚接到一个电话，我的女友正坐在车里
And it says"Serge" but Serge with us in the car
电话显示是“Serge”， 但 Serge和我们在一起在车里
I know I might sound like a villain from afar
我知道我从远处听起来可能像个反派
How do I explain that my mechanic is a chick?
我如何解释我的修理工是一个女孩？
r why she callin'me when I don't even own a car because my licence is revoked
或者为什么她打电话给我，而我甚至没有车，因为我的驾照被吊销了？
I mean, how do I explain that I don't want to heal 'cause my identity is pain?
我是说，我如何解释我不想痊愈，因为我的身份就是痛苦？
How doI explain,I mean, how doI explain?
我如何解释，我是说，我如何解释？
I went and hit the streets because I didn't want a boss
我走向街头是因为我不想有老板
I ended up a worker,I was barely gettin'paid
结果我成了一个打工仔，收入微薄
For someone that was two years above me in my age
为比我大两岁的人工作
I didn't even find it strange, Imean, how do I explain?
我甚至不觉得奇怪，我是说，我如何解释？
Fifty-two miles from Marseilles, I'm in Miraval
距离马赛五十二英里，我在米拉瓦尔
Four years, seventeen days, I ain't been around
四年又十七天，我没有在场
I can't lie, it even shocks me that I'm still around
我不能说谎，我竟然还在，这连我自己都感到震惊
I can't lie, it even shocks me how I'm livin' now
我不能说谎，我现在的生活方式让我自己都感到震惊
Starin'at this Rachel Jones painting, I'm sittin'down
我坐着，凝视着这幅蕾切尔·琼斯（RachelJones）的画作
The last thing I drew was a weapon, I'm livin'wild
我最后画的东西是一把武器，我过着狂野的生活
Turned twenty-seven, but I feel like I'm still a child
我二十七岁了，但感觉自己仍是个孩子
In this house out in Central London I can barely afford
在这个我几乎负担不起的伦敦市中心的房子里
Six months sober and I feel like I'm Dave again
清醒了六个月，我感觉自己又变回了Dave
Drinkin'all my pain and my sorrows away again
再次将我所有的痛苦和悲伤一饮而尽
I got withdrawal symptoms, but they happen at ATMs
我出现了戒断症状，但它们发生在自动取款机旁（指对金钱的渴望）
Next two years, Tll be lookin'ateighty M's
接下来的两年，我将看着八千万（英镑）
Who's the best artist in the world? I'm sayin' Tems
世界上最好的艺术家是谁？我说Tems
Maybe James Blake or Jim, on the day, depends
也许是JamesBlake或Jim（该张专辑的feature们)，取决于那天的情况
Let's see who quits now we ain't gettin' paid again, yeah
让我们看看现在谁会退出，因为我们又没拿到报酬了，耶
I'm just here drinkin' liquor by myself
我只是独自一人在这里喝酒
Is my music just becomin' a depiction of my wealth?
我的音乐是否正成为我财富的写照？
er trust a girl whose lock screen's a picture of herself, I had to learn that stuff m
永远不要相信 一个锁屏是她自己照片的女孩，我必须自己学到这一点
Now I'm sittin' by myself with no girl, like, stuff, I really did this to myself
现在我独自一人坐着，没有女孩，就像，天啊，这真是我自作自受
seven and I'm terrified of livin' by myself'cause there's a kid inside myself I haver
二十七岁，我害怕独居，因为我内心有个孩子我还没治愈
And me and him debate each other
我和他（内心的孩子）互相争论
I can't love myself, I'm made from two people that hate each other
我无法爱自己，我来自两个互相憎恨的人（我的父母）
My parents couldn't even save each other, made each other unhappy
我的父母甚至无法拯救彼此，只是让彼此不快乐
Used to be excited by the block, but size doesn't matter
过去曾因街区而兴奋，但大小不重要
You supplying it or not? Sling a shot, I could have really killed a giant with a rock
你是供应还是不供应？扔出石头， 我本可以真的用一块石头杀死一个巨人
But that's a life that I forgot, and my young boys are slidin' over what?
但那是我遗忘的生活，我的年轻兄弟们正因为什么而键而走险？
I don't know'cause I ain't spoke to him in time
我不知道，因为我有一段时间没和他们说话了
Been afraid of gettin' older, scared of bein'left behind
一直害怕变老，害怕被落下
And then I, tsk, and then I question, will I live my life in resent?
然后我 唉，然后我质疑，我的生活会活在怨恨中吗？
Is anybody ever gonna take my kindness for strength?
是否有人会把我的善良视为力量？
I gave Tisha the world, it weren't enough and then she went
我给了Tisha整个世界，但这不够，然后她离开了
Everybody's makin'content,but nobody's content
每个人都在制造内容，但没有人感到满足
Safe space, Can I vent? It crept up
这是一个安全的空间，我可以发泄一下吗？它悄悄地发生了
My girl cheated on me when I was next up
在我即将成功时，我的女友背叛了我
It made me want her even more, man, it's messed up
这让我更想要她，天啊，这太糟了
I still walk around the Vale with my chest out
我仍然挺着胸膛在Vale街区走动
I don't wanna leave my house because l'm stressed out
我不想离开我的家，因为我压力很大
You done me dirty and you didn't even tell a lie
你对我做了龌龊的事，甚至没有撒谎
It ain't about what you said, it's what you left out
问题不在于你说了什么，而在于你遗漏了什么
My whole life, I been feelin' like I'm left out
我一生都感觉自己被排除在外
If you fool around with another girl, she say you cheated on her
如果你跟另一个女孩玩暖味，她说你背叛了她
And if she fool around with another man, she say she stepped out
如果她跟另一个男人玩暖味，她却说她只是出去走走
And if you askin'"bout Dave, they say,"The best out"
如果你问起Dave，他们会说：“最棒的
and I survived all these eras because I barely made any, I'm just speakin'how
耶，我熬过了所有这些时代，因为我几乎没赚什么钱， 我只是说出我的感受
Yeah,messed up,speakin'howIfeel
耶，搞砸了，说出我的感受
Recordin' till the morning,I ain't even had a meal
录音直到早上，我甚至还没吃饭
I dropped Joni home and fell asleep behind the wheel
我送Joni回家，却在方向盘后睡着了
Drivin' at a hundred an hour, I switched gears
以一百英里的时速驾驶，我换了挡
I ain't spoke to 169 in six years
我六年没和169（Dave之前的制作人）说过话了
Don't even get me started on, this stuff's weird
别让我提起 这太奇怪了
Call me what you want, but with music, I'm sincere
随便你怎么叫我，但在音乐上，我是真诚的
You wanna know the reason it's taken me four years?
你想知道我花了四年的原因吗?
It's not'cause I'm surrounded by yes-men and sycophants
不是因为我被马屁精和谄媚者包围
It's'cause I'm with producers and people that give a damn
是因为我和那些真正在乎的制作人与人在一起
It's me who's gotta carry the pressure, I live with that
是我必须承受这份压力，我接受这个事实
was the song we could give the fans when I was out there gettin' stood up by ar
我所想的只是我们能给粉丝的歌，即使我在外面被比我名气小的艺人放鸽子
I don't want no girls around when my nieces, they visit man
当我的侄女们来访时，我不希望有任何女孩在场
They might see the way that I'm livin', I figured that
她们可能会看到我的生活方式，我明白了
I wanna be a good man, but I wanna be myself too
我想成为一个好人，但我也想做我自己
And I don't think that I can do both, sol can't let her too close
而且我认为我不能两者兼顾，所以我不能让她太靠近
It hurts, but I'm still movin', feel like it's me versus me and I'm still losin'
很痛，但我仍在前行，感觉是我和我在对抗，而我仍在输
Yo, my boy, it's Josiah, whatyou sayin'
哟，我的兄弟，我是Josiah，你最近怎么样
You know man had to check you on your freaking birthday, my boy
你知道我必须在你生日这天给你发消息，我的兄弟
More life, my guy
生命万岁，我的老弟
Man soon out, don't even watch that
我很快就出来了，不用担心这个
What you sayin', though, bro?
不过你想说什么呢，兄弟？
you got space on one of them eight-minute, nine-minute tracks to give man a s
我知道你那八分钟、九分钟的歌曲里有空间给我一个致敬
Tell the people'dem my story
告诉人们我的故事
Dem man already know what I was on, the mandem know, my ting
他们都知道我在做什么，兄弟们知道，我的事情
C'mon, bro,I know you got me
来吧，兄弟，我知道你罩着我
Aight, lastly, my sis', Tamah
好了，最后，我的妹妹，Tamah
I beg you check in with her, please, make sure she's blessed
我求你跟她联系一下，拜托，确保她得到祝福
While l'm gone, make sure she's safe
在我离开的时候，确保她的安全
Ayy, soon home, my boy, love
嗨，很快就回家了，我的兄弟，爱你